Alina Gorelik

Okemos, MI 48864 | (517) 505-0309 | agorelik2@gmail.com

Summary

Strong programming and problem-solving skills proven under high-pressure environments. My passion for web development and continuous learning led me to challenge myself with acquiring the latest web development techniques. In November of 2020, I have completed a Full Stack Web Development certificate course from Michigan State University.

Technical Skills

MySQL, MongoDB, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Git, GitBash, VSCode. Previous working experience in ColdFusion, ASP, and SQL Server.

Experience

Associated Bag Company, Milwaukee, WI

Independent Programming Contractor

June 2006 - August 2012

Senior Programmer-Analyst

March 2002 - June 2006

- Developed company's first e-commerce site using Microsoft Commerce Server
- Investigated and analyzed application alternatives to propose best design
- Translated corporate requirements into application specifications

Programmer-Analyst

April 1997 - March 2002

- Designed and customized software for Sales, Purchasing, Inventory, and Accounting
- Maintained and expanded company's SQL, Access and Progress databases
- Completed report requests for Finance, Sales, Customer Service, and Purchasing

Education

Michigan State University Web Development Certificate

June 2020 - November 2020

Full-Stack web development crash course that covered the latest technologies including HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, GitBash.

Milwaukee Business Technical Institute, Milwaukee, WI

Business Computer Programming Certificate, March 1997

Minsk State Pedagogical University, Minsk, Belarus

Bachelor of Science in Physics, Minor in Computer Science

Strengths

Fast Learner, Self Motivated, Excellent Team Worker, Highly Organized, Detail Oriented